vu.edu.au 2013-06-29

# Privacy | Victoria University | Melbourne Australia

## Website Privacy Statement

As a user of the VU websites, your privacy is protected by the Information Privacy Act 2000 (Vic) and the University's [Privacy Policy](http://wcf.vu.edu.au/GovernancePolicy/PDF/POU090123000.PDF).  This statement provides you with information on how the University handles your information when you access its websites.

### Information automatically logged

  * The University may make a record of your visit and log any of the following information for statistical and business purposes - the user's address, the user's domain name, IP address, the date and time of the visit, the pages accessed and documents downloaded, the previous site visited and the type of browser used.  Identification of the user may also be requested and logged.
  * Information about your visit to the website may also be logged by an external service provider that produces to the University de-identified statistical analysis about users' online experiences and trends.
  * If you are not a student or staff member and you send us a message, the University will record your email address.

### Security Information

University sites have security measures in place against the loss, misuse and alteration of information. A login name and password are required to visit secure areas. Staff and students should ensure that passwords are kept confidential.

### Cookies

  * A cookie is a small message given to your web browser by our web server. The browser stores the message in a text file and the message is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. It is possible to disable the acceptance of cookies by your web browser, however, doing so may restrict your ability to access some web pages.
  * Some University sites are access restricted. These sites may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interest. Cookies may also be used for authentication purposes and to improve security during a visitor's session online.
  * Cookies may store the following information: session (numbered key) and duration. A numbered key is a unique server generated number used to track your current session. The session key can be linked back to a user's login identification.
  * Unique identifiers (such as log-in name and password) are collected from web site visitors to verify a user's identity and for use as account numbers in our record system.
  * Unique identifiers are also used to access stored information about a visitor's preferences to enable the dynamic display of the site according to your preferences when you return.

### External Links

Some University sites contain links to other sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of other sites.

### Public Forums

Some University sites may have chat rooms, forums, on-line teaching environments, message boards and news groups available to their users.  Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these arenas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when disclosing your personal information.

## Freedom of Information (FOI)

Under the Victorian Freedom of Information Act (1982), you have general rights to request information held by VU.

The Act has four main functions: 

  * to provide a general right of access to documents
  * to enable individuals to amend incorrect information about them held by government
  * to provide rights of appeal in relation to the previous two functions
  * to require agencies to publish certain details about themselves and their functions 

### Information about the University

We aim to create an open and accountable culture by providing easily accessible information about the University.

VU makes a variety of information and documents available to its stakeholders as part of normal administrative processes. Much of our information is readily available to the public on this website, and also upon request. [University policies](http://wcf.vu.edu.au/GovernancePolicy/) can also be viewed by the public.

The University Archives holds a collection of records that are not required for the day-to-day business of the University, but are still worthy of preservation. For enquiries about what records are held and how these can be accessed, you can [contact the Archivist](http://gpps.vu.edu.au/freedom/cid/9/parent/0/t/freedom).

### Public inquiries

The University endeavours to meet all reasonable requests for access to information through normal administrative arrangements.

However, the University has many documents that cannot be made available through routine requests.  Some of these documents may hold a special interest for researchers and historians and can be made available upon request, without the need to lodge a formal application.

[Read more about public inquiries](http://gpps.vu.edu.au/freedom/cid/13/parent/0/t/freedom), and get contact details for written requests.

### Your personal information

VU staff are generally able to gain access to personal information about themselves that is held by the University without having to make a FOI application.

Past and present students who want to access personal information that is held by the University without having to make a FOI application should contact the [appropriate officer.](http://gpps.vu.edu.au/freedom/cid/14/parent/0/t/freedom)

### Request access to documents

Preliminary inquiries concerning FOI requests should be made to the [FOI coordinator.](http://gpps.vu.edu.au/freedom/cid/15/parent/1/t/freedom) Formal requests for access to documents in the University's possession should be made in writing.
